<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>juliambrown</title>
    <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on juliambrown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliambrown.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How do I get the data: IMG</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/img_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/img_api/</guid>
      <description>I recently started a project with collaborators whose data was sequenced at JGI, and available through the IMG. Their project was stalled because they could not get all of the data they&amp;rsquo;d sequencenced from JGI downloaded onto on site storage for tailored bioinformatics analyses.
The scale of the project was not enormous given how much sequencing is done these days, 17 metagenomes, but they wanted to have both reads, assembled contigs and assembly QC information, such as read coverage profiles per contig (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my website, I&amp;rsquo;m so happy you&amp;rsquo;ve stopped by to visit.
As this website is fresh, and I am not yet sure where I plan to take it, I will begin it all by introducing myself. I am a research scientist at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences in Maine, USA and a mother of two little girls, regretably trying to do it all.
The image for this post is a photo I took in March, 2021 at my favorite hiking spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a Research Scientist at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences.
My background. I earned a PhD in Microbiology from Cornell, then held a year-long postdoctoral position at Albert Einstein College of Medicine. From there, I pivoted from the traditional academic route to take a position as a Bioinformatician at the Single Cell Genomics Center at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences in East Boothbay, Maine. For SCGC, I took on an array of responsibilities and research, from maintaining and scripting for the center&amp;rsquo;s Laboratory Information Management System, to developing, updating and maintaining standardized bioinformatics workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/research/</guid>
      <description>The image at the top of this page is a microscopy slide created from half a teaspoon of seawater. In this image, the larger dots are bacteria. The smaller dots, resembling distant stars within the frame, are viruses. There about 10 times as many viruses in this image as bacteria, though one may note that there are lot of both in this half a teaspoon of water!
When you step into the ocean on planet Earth, you are stepping into an ocean of viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
