<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>juliambrown</title>
    <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on juliambrown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://juliambrown.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logistics</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/logistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/logistics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m feeling as you would if you were to show up early to a good friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding. You know that there are a lot of logistics to coordinate and small crises to solve. You want to help, and to be a part of things, but you don&amp;rsquo;t really have a good picture of everything that needs to happen, and so the best thing to do is to stay out of the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boarding Atlantis</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/to_sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/to_sea/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, my friend and collaborator, Maria, approached me about joining a research cruise she was leading to the Eastern Tropical North Pacific oxygen minimum zone. She was leading a very comprehensive project looking at microbe-driven biogeochemical processes, and wanted to add a virus component to the project. She was wondering if I could be the person to make that happen.
I&amp;rsquo;d recently returned to work after maternity leave, and with a infant at home, my immediate reaction was, &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/blog/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my website, I&amp;rsquo;m so happy you&amp;rsquo;ve stopped by to visit.
Let me introduce myself. I am a research scientist at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences in Maine, USA and a mother of two under 5.
The image for this post is a photo I took in March, 2021 at my favorite hiking spot. I try to visit this spot at least once a month regardless of the season, and use my time in the woods to reorganize my thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a Research Scientist at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences focused on understanding the roles of microbes and viruses using multi-omics techniques.
I earned a PhD in Microbiology from Cornell, then held a year-long postdoctoral position at Albert Einstein College of Medicine. From there, I pivoted from the traditional academic route to take a position as a Bioinformatician at the Single Cell Genomics Center at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences in East Boothbay, Maine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/pages/research/</guid>
      <description>When you step into the ocean on planet Earth, you are stepping into an ocean of viruses. Roughly 50 million viruses are suspended within every teaspoon of seawater. The vast majority of these viruses infect microscopic organisms. Their complex relationship with hosts, ecosystems and biogeochemistry make them one of the least understood components of environments around the globe.
The image at the top of this page is a microscopy slide created from half a teaspoon of seawater.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
