<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Features on juliambrown</title>
    <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Features on juliambrown</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Begin Again</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/begin_again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/begin_again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve begun a new position at Bigelow Laboratory for Ocean Sciences as a Senior Research Scientist. This is a big change in roles, as I now have the resouces I need to build an independent lab group and research program. I am thus transitioning this website from a personal one to a lab website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And even more exciting is that I&amp;rsquo;m hitting the ground running. We are actively collecting samples for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://juliambrown.github.io/en/projects/microbes_from_space&#34;&gt;NASA-funded research project&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; underway in collaboration with the Marine Optics Lab at Bigelow. Check-out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigelow.org/news/articles/2025-06-26.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in Bigelow&amp;rsquo;s Transect Magazine for a write-up on the story behind getting this research off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approach</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you step into the ocean on planet Earth, you are stepping into an ocean of viruses. Roughly 50 million viruses are suspended within every teaspoon of seawater. The vast majority of these viruses infect microscopic organisms. Their complex relationship with hosts, ecosystems and biogeochemistry make them one of the least understood components of environments around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The image at the top of this page is a microscopy slide created from half a teaspoon of seawater. In this image, the larger dots are bacteria. The smaller dots are viruses. There about 10 times as many viruses in this image as bacteria, though one may note that there are lot of both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join us!</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brown will be recruiting an experienced research associate or post doc to join the team within the next 6 months for a two year position investigating marine viruses in low oxygen systems and other areas of marine viral ecology and genomics. If you are interested please email julia [at] bigelow [dot] org.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Ocean Microbes using Satellites</title>
      <link>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/microbes_from_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://juliambrown.github.io/en/features/microbes_from_space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Satellite oceanography has revolutionized our ability to study phytoplankton communities and organic matter in the oceans across large spatial scales and time, yet there remains a gap in the ability to monitor and predict the diversity of the microbial communities that underpin ocean food webs using satellite observational tools. This matters because experimental and observational studies indicate that the source, quality, and quantity of organic matter influences taxonomic and functional diversity changes of microbial communities, which in turn affects biogeochemical cycling, so the strength of this correlation needs to be better understood for modeling responses to climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
